JAIMIE L. BERTOLI

973.738.2187 | Jaimie.bertoli@gmail.com | jaimiebertoli.com | github.com/Jaibean | linkedin.com/in/jaimie-bertoli

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

5+ years experienced pragmatic developer in coding, design, and version control. Creative and solutions-driven individual with the planning and delivery of web applications. Demonstrated achievements of leading, motivating, and managing diverse teams of professionals specific to researching different software programs and sustaining software documentation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

Programming/Development: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, WordPress, AEM, RESTful APIs, C# **Frameworks/Libraries:** Django, Flask, Bootstrap, React, jQuery, JSON, .NET, ASP.NET, Entity

Database: SQL, MySQL, SQLite3, MS SQL Server **Cloud:** AWS Cloud Practitioner in progress

IDEs: Visual Studio, VS Code, PyCharm, Dreamweaver, IDLE

Project Management: Agile/Scrum, Azure DevOps, JIRA, CI/CD, Trello

Version Control: Git, GitHub, BitBucket

Interests: Web App development, Data Analytics, Cloud Setup, Front-end development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

A Free Bird | Brooklyn, NY

Python / Django Developer Internship

July 2021 - Current

Re-doing web app for the non-profit that connects art and music tutors to children facing cancer treatment. Utilizing GitHub, Django, Python, Bootstrap, HTML, Heroku, Cloudflare, AWS, and Salesforce. Part-time volunteer engineer. <u>Afreebird.org</u>

- Deployed form modals that persist to the database with front-end updates. Working on log-in portal and embedding video game.
- SCRUM Master for weekly and bi-weekly sprints, organized through Trello
- Awarded Volunteer of the Month: October 2021

Prosper I.T. Consulting | Remote

Python Developer Internship

January 2021 - April 2021

Utilized Django MVT architectural design pattern and Google Books API to create a database driven web application that keeps track of books in personal libraries.

- Skillset: Python, Django, JSON, HTML, CSS, Git, Azure DevOps, RESTful APIs
- Agile sprint using Azure DevOps to organize project requirements, stories, job boards, and version control.
- Leveraged Azure for version control and slack for team communication.
- Code Summary: Link

C# Developer Internship

Utilized Entity Framework Code First to create the foundation of a web application to be managed like a CMS for a theater company.

- Skillset: C#, .NET, MVC, Entity, Azure DevOps, HTML, CSS, Razor
- CRUD functionality implemental for each Area in the application. Three main Areas split between team members and broken down into stories.

J.P. Morgan & Chase Co. | Wilmington, DE

August 2016 - October 2020

Web Developer & Marketing Associate, August 2019 – September 2020

Built interactive web promotions and static web pages in Adobe Experience Manager. Hand coded components in Dreamweaver with HTML and CSS. Tested, debugged, and deployed campaigns with DevOps. Partnered with international

new hires in India to expand the web team. Trained new hires via Zoom calls and instructional documents I designed and managed.

- Analytics implementation in AEM with JavaScript for campaigns.
- Led 5 different quarterly campaigns and daily SCRUM calls.
- Wrote Agile flow process to improve efficiency of project timeline.
- Developed and implemented version control processes and wrote documentation for reference.

Junior Software Developer, August 2016 - August 2019

Front end coder for internal channels of marketing distribution. Managed relationships and communication between backend and front-end developers. Hand-coded Emails for cross lines of business and internal communications.

- Moved external operations in house saving the company 5 grand per project. Built over 100 projects a month.
- Released XML flex app assets through terminal packaging.
- Built web assets in HTML and CSS. Quality Checked using Litmus, Text-wrangler, and Photoshop.
- Team lead for job intake allocation and served as team solution specialist.
- Automated URL builder with a Visual Basic Macro in Excel that turned a 5 hour job into a half hour job.

Anchor Moving & Storage | Moorestown, NJ Business Systems Analyst

January 2016 - July 2016

Created a WordPress site using HTML and CSS. Wrote website copy and designed imagery using Photoshop. Enhanced online presence through embedment of SEOs on web content.

- Created print ads for South Jersey Biz monthly issues using Photoshop facilitating each month's theme.
- Designed new postcards and business cards for re-branding of the moving line with Photoshop and Vista Print editing.
- Built and implemented monthly e-mail marketing campaigns utilizing HTML, and inline CSS.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Marketing Information Systems, and Advertising

The Rohrer College of Business, Rowan University | Glassboro, NJ University Scholar Cum Laude, Dean's List

Software Developer Boot Camp

The Tech Academy | Remote

Six-month intensive program on software development with courses in Computer Science, HTML5, CSS3/Bootstrap, JavaScript/jQuery/JSON/React, SQL/SQLite3, Python/Django, C#, MVC, Git, GitHub,

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Synergia Sites | Remote Web Developer

October 2020 - Current

Building a digital portfolio for artists by hand coding and utilizing WordPress, deployed on my server space.

- Sibelyalin.com built using WordPress for a multimedia artist.
- Jaimiebertoli.com personal portfolio built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Godni.World built using WordPress with another developer

American Marketing Association, Rowan University | Glassboro NJ Webmaster

September 2012 - May 2016

- Created the club website using HTML5 and Wix CMS to distribute information and job postings.
- Awarded 4th place for outstanding website among the National AMA Chapters in 2016.